<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Emanuel Mairoll on [root&amp;#64;emanuelmairoll.at]#</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Emanuel Mairoll on [root&amp;#64;emanuelmairoll.at]#</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>© 2023 Emanuel J. Mairoll</copyright><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Experience</title><link>/experience/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/experience/</guid><description>This comprehensive (and still incomplete) list represents a wide range of technologies that I have either used extensively, am familiar with, or have had some experience with throughout my career. The list encompasses various areas, such as frontend and backend development, mobile development, databases, cloud and hosting services, operating systems, containerization and orchestration, and more.
&lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
Backend Development Kotlin Go Java C++ Python Lua Bash/Zsh &lt;?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
Mobile Development Swift Objective-C UIKit SwiftUI Java Kotlin Jetpack Compose &lt;?</description></item><item><title>Resume</title><link>/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/resume/</guid><description> Education # Time Period Institution 09/2006 - 07/2008 Volksschule Ostermiething 09/2008 - 07/2010 Volksschule Oberndorf 09/2010 - 07/2014 SHS Oberndorf 09/2014 - 06/2019 HTBLuVA Salzburg - Biomedical Engineering 10/2021 - present Paris Lodron University Salzburg - Computer Science Internships # Time Period Institution 07/2016 - 08/2016 Raiffeisen Technik-Zentrum 08/2017 - 09/2017 B&amp;amp;R Industrial Automation 08/2018 - 09/2018 Paris Lodron University Salzburg - WaveLab Work Experience # Time Period Details 07/2019 - 06/2020 Civil Service (regular and extraordinary) 06/2018 - 03/2020 Lighting technician - Johnnys Disco nightclub 09/2020 - 12/2020 Raiffeisen - ORG/IT Software development 01/2021 - present Authentic Vision - Engineering Projects # Authentic Vision # Improved the iOS app and rebuilt the complete UI using SwiftUI Restructured the backend to enable &amp;ldquo;Distributed Authentication&amp;rdquo; Conducted extensive refactoring to adapt to the new backend infrastructure and remove outdated libraries Extracted efficient Kotlin microservices from the Java monolith Implemented a versatile scripting configuration system Built a Go service that allows internal app distribution Raiffeisen # Developed Spring Boot microservices for security-critical data processing in the banking environment Modernized and maintained React- and JSF-based web applications for &amp;ldquo;Customer Relationship Management&amp;rdquo; Ensured the quality of existing and new software through continuous and automated testing of components and their integration Agile, organized, and cooperative work in a Scrum team</description></item><item><title>Under Construction ;-)</title><link>/blog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/</guid><description/></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>/aboutme/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/aboutme/</guid><description>Technology, in every way, shape and form, has always been my passion. Imagine me at seven years old, tinkering around with cables, batteries, light bulbs and speakers, building primitive &amp;ldquo;alarm systems&amp;rdquo; onto doors, triggering when somebody would open them.. well to the annoyance of my parents. :D
I soon moved into computers, realizing that this omnious thing called &amp;ldquo;Internet&amp;rdquo; could answer me everything that I wanted to know. Often I spent hours into the night (which back then meant nine o&amp;rsquo;clock of course) sitting in front of the screen, digging into everything that interested me.</description></item></channel></rss>